mail2world.com 2015-11-04

# Mail2World Privacy Policy

**Conduct Policy** **Spam Policy**

**Fraud Policy**

**Privacy Policy**

**Terms of Service**

| 

**Mail2World Privacy Policy**  

**Effective August 7, 2015**

**Mail2World, Inc. TRUSTe Privacy Program.** This privacy policy describes how Mail2World, Inc. (Mail2World) collects and uses the personally identifiable information you provide on our website [www.Mail2World.com](http://www.mail2world.com/). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personally identifiable information and how you can access and update this information. 

The TRUSTe program covers the website www.mail2world.com and does not cover information that may be collected behind the login and www.mail2world.net. 

In order to view our relationship with TRUSTe please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe seal. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this policy, contact Mail2World by email at [policy@mail2world.com](mailto:policy@mail2world.com). If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

**Mail2World, Inc. EU Safe Harbor compliance.** Mail2World, Inc. EU Safe Harbor Affirmative Statement. Mail2World, Inc. complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personally identifiable information from European Union member countries. Mail2World, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Mail2World's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. 

**Third Party Advertising**  
We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) ). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads .

**Cookies and other Tracking Technologies**  
Cookies are pieces of information that a Web site transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies enable Mail2World's privacy, personalization and preferences capabilities. Once a user is logged into a Mail2World email account, our cookies tie in with that user's member ID, which is related to a username and email address. Personally Identifiable Information is also tied to a user's IP address for security purposes, such as investigating illegal use of an email account or when a user asks us to find out if an intruder has accessed his or her account. Mail2World uses cookies so that you can maintain your identity (and thus, your privacy, personalization and preferences) throughout the site. For example, we identify you as a member, a system administrator or a content administrator, and those identities determine what you may do while on the site. In another example, we know which choices you made under the 'Options' section of the site, so those preferences will be carried along with your throughout the email service 

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Mail2Wolrd and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. 

We use cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference), and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited . 

**Log Files**. As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you. 

**Local Storage Objects (Flash)**. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click here: 

<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118>

**Mail2World is committed to protecting your privacy.** We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. If you have any questions about the security of your personally identifiable information, you can contact us at [support@mail2world.com](mailto:support@mail2world.com).

To ensure that you, a registered user of Mail2World.com, receive top performance without compromising security and confidentiality, we are committed to the Mail2World Privacy Principles, which are as follows:

 **Privacy Principles**

**Principle 1.**   **We will limit the collection and use of customer information to the minimum required for us to deliver superior service to you.** We will share your personally identifiable information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. Mail2World will explicitly ask for information that personally identifies you (Personally Identifiable Information), such as your first and last name, state and zip code (or country and postal code for non-U.S. residents), gender, year of birth, and occupation. This information will be collected during the account registration process. You may update this information at any time from within your Mail2World account by clicking the 'Options' button on the navigation bar, and then clicking on the 'Profile' link.

We use this information to (Choose Relevant Items) 

  * Fulfill your order
  * Send you an order confirmation
  * Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Send product updates
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Administer your account
  * Send you a newsletter
  * Send you marketing communications
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Conduct research and analysis
  * Display content based upon your interests
  * Facilitate your transactions with other users
  * List you in our member directory made available only to other members 

**Principle 2.**   **You may access your Personally Identifiable Information at any time to make changes.** If your Personally Identifiable Information changes, you may update this information at any time from within your Mail2World account by clicking the 'Options' button on the navigation bar, and then clicking on the 'Profile' link. To change your email address, you must create a new account and select a new domain name, etc. If you no longer desire our service, please email your request to delete your email address and Personally Identifiable Information along with your username and password to our Customer Support Dept. at [support@mail2world.com](mailto:support@mail2world.com) or by contacting us by postal mail at Customer Support Dept., Mail2World, Inc., 10960 Wilshire Bl., 9th Floor, Los Angeles, CA 90024. Or you may simply not use your email account, in which case it will automatically deactivate after 30 days of non-use. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active and in good standing to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

**Principle 3.**   **We will safeguard any information that you provide to us.** Your Personally Identifiable Information and email address is used only for demographic statistics, to display appropriate individualized advertisements, process credit card payments and purchase domain names. Mail2World keeps all of your Personally Identifiable Information and email addresses private, sharing that information only as necessary . These companies are authorized to use your personally identifiable information only as necessary to provide these servcies to us. Mail2World will not disclose your Personally Identifiable Information or email address unless acting under a good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Mail2World; (3) enforce the Mail2World Terms of Service; or (4) act to protect the interests of its members or others. We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the website. Mail2World does not store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. Your friend may contact us at [policy@Mail2World.com](mailto:policy@Mail2World.com) to request that we remove this information from our database . 

If Mail2World is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information. 

**Principle 4.**   **We will always maintain control over the confidentiality of our customer information. We may facilitate relevant offers from companies that you have expressed interest in.** Mail2World will not send you any unsolicited information, including email, except as mentioned below. New users will receive a Mail2World welcome letter explaining the features provided by the service. Under exigent circumstances, Mail2World may be required to send you information about the service or your account. As a feature of the service, Mail2World will provide customers with a membership email newsletter, upgrade notifications and other service-related information. Mail2World will not send you unsolicited email regarding any commercial offers or advertisements at any time.

**Principle 5.**   **The Mail2World contains links to other web sites and assumes no responsibility for content or policies of those sites.** Please note that when you follow one of these links, you are entering another web site. We encourage you to read the Privacy Policies on the other sites, as their privacy policies may be different than ours.

**Principle 6.**   **You may opt-out of receiving all Mail2World communications except the 'Site & Service' administrative notifications. Site & Service notifications are critical to your email service operation.** Other communications include the Mail2World Membership Newsletter. 

You may opt out of receiving the newsletter by selecting 'Options' on the Mail2World site, clicking on 'Profile' to access your personal profile information, or you can contact us at [support@mail2world.com](mailto:support@mail2world.com) and finally, deselecting the newsletter option (unchecking the checkbox) near the bottom of the registration page.

**Principle 7.**   **You will be notified of any changes in our email practices, Personally Identifiable Information collection processes, the way we use that information or our privacy policy itself.** If we decide to make changes in our email practices, we will post those changes to this privacy policy, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If we make material changes to the way we use your email address, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page, prior to the change becoming effective. If we are going to use your Personally Identifiable Information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our web site notifying users of the change prior to it becoming effective. In some cases where we post the notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

**Principle 8.**   **Surveys and Contests will be featured from time to time on the Mail2World site. Mail2World will manage all information collected during those activities.** If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). There may be instances where when the information is shared with partners in specific projects (contests, for example, where a third-party becomes a substantial partner). These third parties will be prohibited from using our users' personally identifiable information for any other purpose. 

**Principle 9.**   **We will attempt to keep customer files complete, up-to-date, and accurate. We will inform our customers how to notify us about errors, which we will promptly correct.** If at any time you believe that Mail2World has not adhered to these principles, please notify us by email at [policy@Mail2World.com](mailto:policy@mail2world.com), and we will use all commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and correct the problem.

If you have questions about this policy, please email us at [support@mail2world.com](mailto:support@mail2world.com).

For more information about our privacy policy, see the following Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs).

* * *

**Frequently Asked Questions** **What are Cookies?**

Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies can make a Website more useful by storing information about your preferences on a particular site. The use of cookies is an industry standard, and many major web sites like Mail2World use them to provide useful features for their customers.

Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user's computer. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies. However, you may not be able to take full advantage of a Web site if you do so.

Once a user is logged into a Mail2World email account, our cookies tie in with that user's member ID, which is related to a username and email address. Personally identifiable Information is also tied to a user's IP address for security purposes, such as investigating illegal use of an email account or when a user asks us to find out if an intruder has accessed his or her account.

Mail2World uses cookies so that you can maintain your identity (and thus, your privacy, personalization and preferences) throughout the site. For example, we identify you as a member, a system administrator or a content administrator, and those identities determine what you may do while on the site. In another example, we know which choices you made under the 'Options' section of the site, so those preferences will be carried along with your throughout the email service. Cookies enable Mail2World's privacy, personalization and preferences capabilities.

 **How does Mail2World use my Contacts information?**

Mail2World stores, processes and maintains your Contacts data in order to provide the service to you. Any third-party contact's personally identifiable information that you may have entered into Contacts (e.g., friends, family, coworkers) is private and is not used for any purpose by Mail2World. The information collected in our Add Contact form includes names, titles, email addresses, phone numbers, IM names, Skype names, mailing addresses, birthdays, anniversaries, names of spouses or partners, employer's company and department, professional titles, work addresses, work web site, work manager's name, fax number and pager number. 

**When I import my address book from another email account, how is that information handled?**

Mail2World offers an Import Contacts feature to help you keep in touch with your contacts that you may have listed in other email address books. Through our Import/Export Wizard, we make it easy for you to manually step through the process of accessing your contact information (e.g., Gmail account, .CSV file, vCard), then the Wizard automatically imports the contact information (i.e., contact names, addresses, phone numbers, fax numbers, etc.) into your Mail2World Contacts. 

Mail2World's Contacts also allows you to request updates from your contacts by clicking the Request Update button in a contact's information panel. The invitation to update will be delivered in an email message displaying your "From" name, and the subject line will read: "[Contact's Name]: Update Your Contact Info." 

**Does Mail2World collect other forms of information about its users?**

In addition to the use of Personally identifiable Information to operate the site, Mail2World also gathers anonymous information, which may be used by Mail2World or shared with its advertisers. This is information which does not personally identify you, but which may be helpful for marketing purposes or for improving the services we offer. Generally, this information is collected through "traffic data" or "log files" and may entail the use of "IP addresses", "Protocol version", "Total access time", or other numeric codes used to identify a computer. No tracking technologies are used within email communications our users send out or on pages where email addresses are collected.

**How do I correct or change Personally identifiable Information that I have given to Mail2World?**

You may update this information at any time from within your Mail2World account by clicking the 'Options' button on the navigation bar, and then clicking on the 'Profile' link.

**Is my Personally identifiable Information secure from others using the Mail2World site?**

The security of your Personally identifiable Information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information, such as a credit card number and/or social security number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). To learn more about SSL, follow this link. 

Mail2World follows generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personally Identifiable Information and email addresses you submit to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100-percent secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personally identifiable information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

We limit access to Personally Identifiable Information and email addresses to employees whom we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information. 

If you have any questions about security on the Mail2World Web site, you can send us an email at [support@mail2world.com](mailto:support@mail2world.com) or [click here to use our support form](http://www.mail2world.com/feedback.asp). 

**How is Mail2World registration information used in the Mail2World Directory and how can I remove my name from the Directory?**

During the Mail2World registration process you are given the choice as to whether you want to be listed in the Mail2World Directory. If you did not make a choice during the initial registration process, your registered name and location is listed in the Mail2World Directory. At any time, you can change or remove your personally identifiable information from the Mail2World Directory by clicking the 'Options' button on the navigation bar, and then clicking on the 'Profile' link.

Questions regarding this policy should be directed to [support@mail2world.com](mailto:support@mail2world.com). 

|
